(Production Sponsors)
(Ministry of Culture, Sports and Tourism and KOCCA)
(This is a work of fiction. All names, characters,)
(and incidents are products of the author's imagination.)
(All child actors were accompanied by a guardian,)
(and filmed in accordance with labour laws.)
All right, here's the question.
During a nuclear explosion or powerful lightning...
that can stop phones, microwaves, and even a spaceship in flight,
what's this EM shockwave called?
Looks like Yeon San was quickest on the buzzer again.
(Joo Yeon San, Ban Ji No)
Hey Ji No, please tone it down. This is an educational program.
Joo Yeon San. If you get this right, you will win the title.
That's ten-year-old Joo Yeon San.
This is the first moment in her life she wishes she could delete.
The reason she went on a quiz show she wasn't even interested in...
was her homeroom teacher.
In his first semester after joining, he was really well put together.
Joo Yeon San?
How do you feel?
Feeling confident?
Yes.
(Let's go, Yeon San!)
That's our confident Joo Yeon San. Go ahead and tell us your answer.
My answer is EMP, the electromagnetic pulse.
Correct!
(Let's go, Yeon San!)
This year's champion of the Science Genius Quiz is...
Cheongnyong Elementary's 3rd-grader, Joo Yeon San!
(Joo Yeon San, Ban Ji No)
(Joo Yeon San)
Yes, Joo Yeon San.
Any thoughts on your victory?
- I did get the answer right, but... - But?
Technically speaking, a spaceship in flight wouldn't stop.
As you explained, an EMP is an electromagnetic shockwave.
So the spacecraft's computer systems would shut down,
and the communication systems may fail.
Also, the control systems might malfunction,
but the spaceship wouldn't come to a physical stop.
My, Joo Yeon San, you're quite sharp.
We were just trying to simplify it for our younger audience...
But if it's for elementary students, shouldn't it be more accurate?
This is a science quiz show, after all.
During a nuclear explosion or a powerful lightning...
As you can see, Joo Yeon San could be a bit much back then.
But her teacher was a rare adult who looked upon San with pride.
Natural selection.
Rounded to 233.
First law of thermodynamics!
The number 2 appears p minus 2 times!
That's right! This year's champion of the Science Genius Quiz is...
Cheongnyong Elementary's 3rd-grader, Joo Yeon San!
(Scholarship Certificate)
Joo Yeon San!
The quiz show brought her attention, fame, and even prize money.
She felt on top of the world, posing for a photo with her teacher.
So why does San remember it as such an embarrassing part of her past?
She says even she didn't know at the time...
that it would be the beginning of a disaster.
A poet trying to start a business? Give me a break.
Come on, who knew selling workbooks would be so risky?
(Yeon San is the trend.)
San's father even quit his job.
Swayed by his acquaintances, jumped into the workbook business.
The business, of course, failed.
San's family ended up in a motel.
Maybe it was her environment,
but San had a sexual awakening young.
A short stay?
- She soon learned what it meant... - Hey,
- for couples to check into a motel. - what should order to eat?
How's about something hot?
Something hotter than last night?
And that this was the worst place to run into her teacher.
San?
Vice...
Principal?
They apparently spent...
their room time just trying to keep San quiet.
Should she have been happy that they left and did nothing?
And bittersweetly, this was San's first love.
In middle school, Joo Yeon San was a surprisingly pious churchgoer.
It wasn't so much a belief in a deity,
but more her sheer desperation.
At San's request, because she had terrible acne then,
this scene was recreated using AI.
We appreciate your understanding.
It's also to protect this boy's privacy.
Is that the new Nonghyup branch manager's son?
Yes. He has such a sophisticated air.
With that branch manager's help,
San's parents took over a motel up for auction...
by taking out every loan they could.
And so, San went from living in a motel to the owner's daughter.
But it's not as if San liked him for his family's status.
She said the manager's son had beautifully slender fingers.
His side profile was to die for,
and he looked so beautiful even with his eyes closed...
Wait, what is this?
Wait, no, seriously!
During their performance together, disaster struck.
Their fingers had only brushed against each other.
"What the heck? Get your hands off me!"
Screaming that during the service was, admittedly, San's fault.
They gossiped about how she'd called a perfectly normal guy a pervert.
They said the motel warped her views,
ending her second love like that.
(Korea Science High School)
At 17, San escaped the motel.
She wasn't called the "Quiz King" for nothing.
She entered the notorious Science High School easily.
But she faced prodigies...
who'd studied abroad and mastered calculus.
And apparently, competing with them wasn't easy.
And so, her grades continued to fall.
How can we make a team...
by making a compound from the remaining element symbols?
Let's kill it!
- Are we ready? - She reluctantly participated...
in the KAIST Mentoring Camp.
And there, among all those light-emitting diodes,
- is where she met Chang Yi. - Five, four,
three, two, one!
Team Acetylene and Team Ozone, you both are the winners!
Although he was her age, he was already a KAIST freshman.
Joo Yeon San.
I'm Park Chang Yi.
From earlier... Team Acetylene.
- Yes. - That was...
a lot of fun, wasn't it?
Yes.
- Can I get your phone? - Sorry?
This is my phone number.
Text me when the camp's over.
Let's hang out.
We'll save the rest of the details for another time.
However, the key thing to note here...
is Joo Yeon San's repeating pattern.
Whenever she got involved with a guy who was way too into himself,
the outcome was never good.
(I wish to withdraw from school.)
Based on the data she'd collected over many years,
San had even reached...
- that very conclusion. - It was me...
So why do I find myself with this handsome guy again?
(LOVE.exe)
(Episode 7: A Banana Instead of School Lunch)
You okay?
Is it normal for my heart to be racing like this?
It must be I haven't run in a while.
Sorry. Did I startle you?
But why on earth are you carrying that thing?
(Smooth Taste, Like Dew)
Oh, this.
This person here, you know...
She's the one who came to our school to film that time.
She's super famous.
You know her, right?
I'm a huge fan of her. I really like her.
But it was on the ground by a bar, so I was trying to stand it back up.
For a styrofoam cutout?
I know, but still,
if something that looks human is rolling around on the ground,
it's not a good look, you know?
But some guys were being real jerks...
What the... Why is that over there?
with this.
They kept messing with it, and I couldn't just stand by.
It's hot.
What?
(Smooth Taste, Like Dew)
Now that he's covered it, why does it feel more familiar?
Coming through.
Yes, go ahead.
Now I remember.
Why do I keep acquiring unwanted data?
Sorry?
What did you say?
No, I just...
think I get the picture.
Anyway, I should be heading home.
Turns out my place is this way.
Oh.
Oh, hold on!
I...
I have a favour to ask you.
Can I...
just crash at your place for the night?
I have to go back to the shoot,
and it's a pain to lug all this stuff there.
(Smooth Taste, Like Dew)
(No.1 Soju, made with spring water)
What am I doing?
You were supposed to be filming. Where did you go?
Oh...
I just...
felt so suffocated.
- What? - Hey...
There's no such thing as an eco-friendly golf course.
Even tiny hotels produce a ton of waste.
How is this possible?
I thought I was helping the planet, so I promoted it so hard, you know?
Min Hak, this is no time to be worrying about that stuff.
I have to worry about that stuff.
I'm the ambassador.
- Look at this first. - What is it?
You remember the Yongsan premiere the day you and Jinny...
had that episode?
Yes.
After the main after-party, it seems a small group had another round.
That's when this photo was taken at some market food stall.
That's Timothy.
I'm a huge fan of his.
It hasn't hit the media yet,
but after last year's Busan International Film Festival,
there have been rumours circulating that Jinny and Timothy are an item.
And Jinny's agency has no intention of stopping this rumour at all.
Busan.
Do you mean last year's Busan?
Yes! That was when she was seeing you.
Hey, what the heck is this?
While we were busy with the Quiz King,
she was starting a rumour with Timothy?
What, so Timothy is on a level to have a dating rumour with Jinny,
but you're not?
Don’t you ever join these stupid contests again.
You're just doing someone else's work.
Jinny has been ghosting you lately, right?
But, Timothy?
This is unbelievable.
It felt warmer this time last year. Why is it so cold?
I'm a little cold, too.
Right? It's this weird weather.
It snowed on the first day of class.
- Or we could grab a drink inside? - What?
We could get a room.
A room?
We can grab some soju and snacks and go.
There's a good izakaya nearby. Can't we just go there?
I'd rather we relaxed, just the two of us.
I don't think we're at that stage yet.
Stage?
We've only chatted online. This is our first time meeting.
Can't we just grab a highball at the izakaya tonight?
Okay.
Come on, let's go.
Playing hard to get when she's not even hot...
What?
You just said something.
Just that it's getting chilly.
Something about playing hard to get. You didn't say that?
Fine, I did. I said it.
"Playing hard to get when she's not even hot."
It's not like I'm wrong.
So this is why you acted all gentlemanly.
Hey, we'll never see each other again.
If I knew you were all talk,
I wouldn't have paid for a single drink.
Act precious, then.
But you won't have to worry. Guys won't even look at you.
Hey.
What's this?
Wonder if you taste good?
What do you think he'll taste like?
I think I need a little sample.
Man, but that face...
Oh, never mind.
Can't be a picky eater.
Gil Tan.
Let's go over there and warm up.
I'll get you all nice and hot.
What? Wait?
Hey, where are you going?
You said it was cold. I'll warm you up!
- I'm going home! - Stop!
That one looks so delicious!
(Founders' Hall)
Hello, everyone.
- Lunchtime... - So that jerk asked me to a motel.
Motel at first meeting? Is he nuts?
I know, right?
I was so scared of that psycho,
but a passing neighbour helped me.
A neighbour?
A neighbour and also a colleague, I guess?
Don't tell me it was the Tissue Man?
You two keep bumping into each other.
Today's menu...
(Lunch menu)
Why is everything over ten dollars?
Seriously, I can never get used to these prices.
Seriously, we should start a petition.
Isn't this basically embezzlement?
I wouldn't mind if it were any good.
The bird flu ended ages ago,
and they still won’t give fried egg refills?
Just a banana again today?
"Better to start with a doable plan now than wait for a perfect one."
Is this about not getting the scholarship?
When you have an unexpected expense,
cutting back on eating out is the surest way to save.
Sure.
Will one banana really be enough for you?
Not me. I could never.
Gosh.
Hey, it's been a while since I had cafeteria food.
What's on the menu today?
He is the one, the Tissue Man.
The guy with the dyed yellow hair.
His body is insane.
I thought you liked softer features.
When did I say he was my type?
I'm grateful, so he's on my mind.
My mom always said not to owe anyone anything.
- Hey Gil Tan! - Hey, Min Hak!
- Hey, everyone, say hi. - Hello.
- This is our superstar, Min Hak. - Hello.
So he's friends with Min Hak too. He's such a social butterfly.
I see that.
I thought Min Hak had no friends in the Department of Modelling.
- There's nothing to eat today. - Oh?
- Hey, come by later. - Okay.
(Endless Sparkle, Ultimate Refresh)
Jinny?
What, so Timothy is on a level to have a dating rumour with Jinny,
but you're not?
(Endless Sparkle, Ultimate Refresh)
He must really like Jinny.
A banana in a pouch?
She doesn't even waste a half-eaten banana.
San practices what she preaches,
unlike me and Jinny.
Wait!
Na Rae.
Hey, your legs are really long.
Sorry. I didn't know you were following me.
It's fine.
I need to talk to you privately.
What about?
Who was it again? Paeng Gil Tan?
Are you close with him?
Yes.
So, does he have a girlfriend?
Or someone he's talking to?
Not that I'm interested, of course.
But in case he's interested in me,
then I have to be responsible for my actions.
Is he seeing someone?
- No. - So he's solo!
No, I'm just saying I don't really know.
You don't know? I thought you two were close.
Should I ask him?
- What he thinks of you? - Oh no.
There's no need for that at all.
Aren't you curious?
No, it's just...
Times like these are...
when you really need that Love Alarm.
If we had something like that, we'd avoid any misunderstandings.
Right?
I'm going to go try convince San again.
Anyway, thanks, Min Hak. Get home safe.
Bye.
Hey, man.
Right.
And about that meeting today...
If I'm not absolutely needed...
So, to continue what I was saying,
the Love Alarm,
I'm saying, why can't we make it?
Because I'm kind of desperate.
I'm not a fan.
Setting aside whether we could find a suitable dataset,
the motivation for a gamble that's beyond our abilities...
is just to help your hopeless love life?
I have zero motivation.
Actually...
What?
I'm not sure how much data you'd actually need,
but I feel like you wouldn't need a lot of data to tell...
when someone has a crush.
But to meaningfully quantify that kind of subjective judgment,
you need tons and tons of inductive evidence.
What I'm saying is,
you can't hide your feelings.
Without realising, your eyes are drawn to them,
you hover around,
you keep trying to talk to them.
Your face gets all red, your heart starts pounding...
and you even dream of them, right?
I guess that's true.
But dreaming about someone doesn't necessarily mean you like them.
Instead of that, if we're to make something that reads people's minds,
I'd rather it tell me when a breakup is about to happen.
When the person I like starts to drift away from me,
an alarm or something would go off.
It'd give you a chance to save it.
Or at least give you time to accept it.
It could probably even tell if your partner is cheating.
But I still need a Love Alarm more.
I could totally use it on my dad.
I need to go protest against the merger.
- Just go straight. Go straight. - Straight.
- What? - Go straight.
What's that now?
- How's that? - A little...
- Just a little this way. - This way?
But that idea just now is not actually realistic, is it?
It's not completely out of the question.
What if an app predicted breakups by measuring the emotional distance,
or an app that helps soften the blow of it all?
Yes! That's it, that's exactly it.
It's basically the same logic, but you listen when Min Hak says it.
A couple's message frequency over a specific period of time.
Or the frequency of pet names they use for each other.
Combine health app step-count data with location data from map apps...
to find patterns in the time they spend together.
Changes in their spending history at date spots could also be useful.
So you really can make it.
Good.
No, that's my way of saying we can't.
- Oh. - Look, what I just listed off...
is an insane amount of data.
Even if you could get investors,
it'd be almost impossible to get a private relationship dataset.
In short, it'd be insanely hard.
It was a good idea, though.
Really?
Maybe because I've been thinking about this for so long.
I started by writing down my question like this,
(Why do people who fall in love end up falling apart?)
"Why do people who fall in love end up falling apart?"
I just stared at it and thought.
I see.
If you were to post that on Instagram,
you'd better keep it on your phone.
No, I wasn't going to post it anywhere.
It's just been the biggest question on my mind since I was little.
You said I'm like a blank slate, a blank canvas, right?
No, not at all.
The issue of people getting together and breaking up...
that's been a mystery for humanity since the dawn of time.
I'd look at this and just keep thinking about it.
And whenever an answer came to mind, I'd jot that down, too.
Why bother writing it by hand...
- just to take a picture of it? - I kept thinking...
- You have nice handwriting, though. - what could help our team...
Oh?
This is...
I've wondered about this forever.
I just wish I could figure it out.
Hey, this is surprisingly like the Feynman Algorithm.
- It is. - What?
Feynman? The Feynman Algorithm.
If it's something like that, is it a computer language, too?
Well...
- Pineapple? - Sorry?
"I'm fine..."
- I guess it's not related to that. - Yes.
Hey Min Hak, you're really levelling up.
There's a genius physicist named Richard Feynman.
He said, "With this one algorithm,"
"one could solve any problem in the world."
For real? What is it?
One, write down the problem.
Hold on.
Two, think really hard.
Three, write down the answer.
Great.
You're telling me those three steps can really solve anything?
It's not actually a rule that Mr. Feynman came up with.
It's more of a sarcastic take on how he solved problems.
Still, it's interesting, isn't it?
The important thing is to face the problem head-on.
Exactly. It's surprisingly helpful.
Well...
I have my own version of that.
Look.
This...
I can't see a thing.
Here, look.
(Big problem)
When you write down a big problem in tiny letters like this,
then all those overwhelming worries...
are just tiny words on a page.
Somehow, it makes me feel a little lighter.
Problem.
(Write down problems, big problem)
My worries.
(Worries...)
(Mom: What’s your dad up to? I can't get a hold of him.)
Honey.
What's your dad up to? I can't get a hold of him.
If you see your dad, tell him to call me.
"First, write down the problem."
"Make my problem smaller."
(Joo Yeon San)
("If you can't explain it simply,")
("you don't understand it well enough." Richard Feynman)
There's a genius physicist named Richard Feynman.
He said, "With this one algorithm,"
"one could solve any problem in the world."
What did the number 100 on the cake mean?
Was it a photo celebrating their 100-day anniversary?
No, it can be a niece or nephew's 100-day.
Darn it. That's not the problem right now.
Gosh, this is fun. Hey, if we just sell a bit more,
- we could get all new blinds. - Wait, just the blinds?
Let's go get something good to eat.
Right.
We?
Do you want to play a round of Tekken?
Right now, our anti-merger banner for Central Plaza is more urgent.
Okay.
Why get more stuff? It's a headache to split it all up.
Who will get the Tekken machine? The CompSci Department?
The Model Department?
Why are you thinking of that now?
My parents are divorced, so I know. Dividing assets is a real mess.
Then just don't split up.
What?
Have you been to the Gangwon Branch Campus?
No.
There's one building on a mountain and nothing else around.
A lot of us are professionals, so we have to commute to and from Seoul.
Since transport is bad, many have taken a leave or just dropped out.
We're mad too...
that the school just got rid of the Arts and Sports Campus.
But for us, just getting to come here is a huge opportunity.
So let's just try to enjoy ourselves while we're here, okay?
For someone who said the department jacket was lame,
you sure wear it a lot.
Whatever.
We have to keep selling clothes...
to cover the budget for the anti-merger protest.
Smile.
Say cheese!
Smile. Come on.
I said, smile!
Why won't our engineering school girls smile for the camera?
Requesting assistance.
(San: Requesting assistance)
- What's going on? - What's it about?
My dad's having an affair.
- What? - Out of the blue?
I saw him coming out of a motel with some woman yesterday,
and the problem is when and how to tell my mom.
Dad is cheating.
If I tell Mom the truth, there's a lot to consider.
The basic assumption is that no secret stays hidden forever.
Therefore, there's no happy ending.
Instead, considering my mom's pain,
I'm going to choose the method with the lowest "Unhappy Score."
So, you're trying to quantify your mom's pain?
An optimization problem.
Let's set the emotional damage from the betrayal to negative five.
For example, if I keep this a secret from my mom and she finds out later.
Then on top of the negative five points for Dad's betrayal,
another negative five points should be added for my betrayal.
But Mom and I are blood relatives.
A marriage is a promise, so the impact differs.
So I've given Dad's side a bonus impact value of 1.5.
How long the secret is kept will also be a variable.
Good point.
Learning of Dad's affair right away versus learning of it in ten years,
or on her deathbed.
The shock would be completely different.
But if she finds out as she's dying, the initial shock would be huge,
but the pain wouldn't last long.
So the "Unhappy Score" might be lower.
So what happens to the function once you pass a critical point?
I'll calculate that.
I think I just need to integrate it.
Hey!
Are you guys actual psychopaths?
Who talks about calculus in a situation like this?
- Okay, whatever. Was she pretty? - What?
- Do you have a picture? - A picture of what?
- You didn't take a picture? - No. I saw them from the bus.
Gosh, you all act so smart, but you're completely clueless.
Go sit down, Joo Yeon San.
All right, listen up.
What's the most important thing here?
- The formula? - Hard evidence.
What's the use of crunching numbers?
You need a picture of your dad...
leaving a motel linking arms with another woman...
so he can't deny it, right?
Hey.
Which way are you headed?
I'm going back the way I came.
He said where he was going, but...
They weren't linking arms or anything.
Are you sure your dad is really cheating?
I'm sure about that part, but...
Rosa, Rosa
I'm your one and only rose
If you dare to touch me, you'll be pricked by my thorns
If you want a passionate love
Don't be shy
And hold me in your arms
Rosa, Rosa
I'm your one and only rose
Oh my gosh, what is this crap?
Hey, were you really that into Jinny?
I...
Rosa, Rosa
I'm your one and only rose
If you dare to touch me
Hey, I got a compliment from San today.
She said I had a great idea.
Don't tell me you went to that meeting again.
I thought you were just taking attendance in that class.
I mean...
I just talked with her for a bit after I signed in for class.
Min Hak, I told you, you don't need to get mixed up with them anymore.
That competition and all that...
were for Jinny.
Look, let's just put the past behind us...
and focus on what's ahead.
But what about Feynman...
There.
Do you know the Feynman Algorithm?
I have a lot on my mind.
I know. I think breaking the problem into small pieces...
I need some water.
Seriously, it’s as if age automatically means authority.
Excuse me.
Do you give discounts on personal training here?
I don't think so.
You don't have a blog?
When on earth are you planning on getting this?
Oh, right.
Sorry, I'll grab it soon.
(Sorry, I'll grab it soon.)
He has really thick eyebrows.
She put Jinny on the balcony.
Wait, it's San.